Vipin Varghese

Address: 524 Talbot hall, Talbot street, Dublin 1

PH: +353 892701025 | Email: vipin.kulangara@hotmail.com
Linked-In: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vipin-varghese-86353a166

Github: https://github.com/vipinv5656 | Portfolio: https://vipinvarghese-portfolio.netlify.app

Profile

Experienced Software Engineer with three year (including freelance) of experience in information technology building and maintaining responsive websites. Currently, i enjoy working on technologies like React JS, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, HTML, PHP and Adobe XD.

Having strong professional background with a masters in computing degree from Griffith college Dublin, i am looking forward to work with an organization that provides an opportunity for continuous learning and professional growth using my skills to enhance the growth of the organization as well as self while being resourceful and flexible. I'd like to broaden my skill set to become a full-stack developer, including but not limited to learning node JS and PHP frameworks in response to project demands.

Technical Skills

Front-end: React JS, JavaScript, Redux, Axios, Jquery

Back-end: PHP, Python, Kotlin

Database : PostgreSQL , MySQL , SQLite , Google cloud platform , Firebase

CSS: Tailwind , Bootstrap , Materialize

UX : Adobe XD , Adobe Photoshop

IDE : Visual Studio , Atom , Brackets , Android StudioOther Tools : Github , GitLab , MS Office , Amazon Ec2 instance

Professional Experience

Netware CBS - India , Software Engineer - 06/ 2018 - 07/2020

A banking software development company which offers banking modules to co-operative banks .Here I have worked in different projects using different technologies such as PHP , JavaScript , HTML , Adobe XD .

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Developed and hosted a responsive internal company management application in amazon Ec2 instance.
- Provided updates for the banking module
- Wrote code to implement features and fix bugs in banking module
- Investigated and resolved issues reported by users in complaint box
- Designed and implemented new features
- Database management and writing stored procedures for different modules.

Web Designer -India , 06/2017 - 05/2018

- Worked together to develop websites from the conceptual stages of graphic design to the final hand-off.
- Demonstrate and defend designs and key deliverables to peers .
- Used HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and Photoshop for web development.
- Performed updates for the existing websites.

Education

MSc Computing - Griffith College Dublin - 01/2021 - 08/2022

- Used Python as back-end for web based mini project like drop box clone with Google cloud platform as database
- used Google and Firebase authentication for user authentication management
- Used Kotlin to develop table booking android application with firebase as database and integrated PayPal sandbox payment system as payment gateway as a part of college project.
- Familiar with Agile Methodology

Master of computer Application

SRM Institute, Chennai - India, 04/2017

Bachelor of Computer Application

Hindustan college of Arts and Science, Chennai - India, 04/2014